Guide to the Felix Bloch Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Amaldi, Edoardo.; American Physical Society.; Bohr, Niels, 1885-1962.; Cockcroft, John,, Sir,, 1897-1967.; European Organization for Nuclear Research.; Hansen, W. W. (William Webster), 1909-1949; Heisenberg, Werner, 1901-1976; Hofstadter, Robert,, 1915-1990.; Kirkpatrick, Paul.; Meyerhof, Walter E. (Walter Ernst), 1922-; Perrin, Frances.; Schiff, Leonard I. (Leonard Isaac), 1915-; Shockley, William, 1910-1989.; Stanford Linear Accelerator Center; Stanford University. Department of Physics.; Terman, Frederick Emmons, 1900-1982; Varian Associates..; Webster, David Locke, 1888-1976.; Nuclear induction.; Nuclear magnetic resonance.; Nuclear magnetism.; Physics--Research.; Physics--Study and teaching.; Physics.; Quantum theory.
Collection Contents
- GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE, SERIES I
  This series contains general correspondence arranged in two sections: letters written by Bloch arranged chronologically, and letters written to Bloch arranged alphabetically by correspondent. The correspondence spans about fifty years (1931-1983), but only the period following Bloch's receipt of the Nobel Prize in 1952 is thoroughly documented.
  The designation of Series I correspondence as general refers to the fact that letters dealing with very specific topics have occasionally been filed elsewhere. For example, correspondence which deals solely with the several biographies Bloch wrote about his colleagues is located in Series II under Tributes; letters which deal with a specific research topic are filed in Series III with Bloch's notes; and letters concerning Bloch's membership in, or the administration of, organizations are in Series IV. NOTE: Bloch was often asked by various organizations with which he was affiliated to write recommendations for his colleagues. This material has been included in this series and not in Series IV.
  A few things of which the researcher should be aware when using the General Correspondence series relate to Bloch's method of answering letters. Often he would simply write his response to an incoming letter directly on the letter itself, and then would pass this on to his secretary for typing. In most cases he retained the typed copy, but occasionally the only record of his response is that which appears handwritten on the incoming letter. Also, when Bloch was traveling, his secretary, Marion Middleton, acknowledged all incoming letters. Copies of her responses are filed in folders under her name.
  Of particular interest may be correspondence from 1941 through 1946 when many members of the Stanford physics faculty were engaged in war research. Bloch, William Hansen, Frederick E. Terman, Paul Kirkpatrick, and David L. Webster conducted ongoing departmental meetings by mail. A particular issue of concern during this period, documented in this correspondence, was the feasibility of the High Energy Physics Laboratory at Stanford.
  Between 1954 and 1956, Bloch corresponded with Niels Bohr, Werner Heisenberg, Frances Perrin, Sir Ben Lockspeiser, Sir John Cockcroft, Edoardo Amaldi, C. J. Bakker and others regarding his role as the first Director General of the European Center for Nuclear Research (CERN) in Geneva. Most of this correspondence took place before Bloch left for Switzerland in 1955 and concerned his position as CERN's choice for the Directorship. Almost all of his files from CERN were left there when he returned to Stanford in 1955. He did, however, save selected correspondence, including that with Stanford colleagues. Interesting letters regarding the preliminary planning of the Stanford Linear Accelerator Center are located in the files of Robert Hofstadter, Walter Meyerhof, Leonard Schiff, and other members of the physics department.
  - OUTGOING CORRESPONDENCE
    - 1931-43 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1945-47 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1948-49 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1950-52 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - January-February 1954 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - March-April 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - May 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - June 1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - July 1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - August-October 1954 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - November-December 1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - January-March 1955 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - April-August 1955 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - September-October 1955 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - November 1955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - December 1955 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - January-February 1956 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - March-June 1956 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - July-September 1956 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - October 1956 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - November-December 1956 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - January-February 1957 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - March-April 1957 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - May-December 1957 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - January-August 1958 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - September 1958-February 1959 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - March-December 1959 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - January-June 1960 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - July-December 1960 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - January-July 1961 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - August-December 1961 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - 1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1963 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1964 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - January-May 1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - June-December 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - January-April 1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - May-December 1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - January-October 1967 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - November-December 1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - February-June 1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - July-September 1968 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - October-December 1968 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - January-April 1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - May-December 1969 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - January-May 1970 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - June-December 1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - January-June 1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - July-December 1971 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - January-April 1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - May-August 1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - September-December 1972 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - January-April 1973 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - May-August 1973 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - September-December 1973 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - 1974 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - January-September 1975 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - October-December 1975 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - January-May 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - September-December 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1977 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - January-June 1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - July-December 1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 1981 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 1982 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 1983 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - INCOMING CORRESPONDENCE
    - Aaserud, F. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Abragam, A. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Ac-Al (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Amaldi, E. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Am-An (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Ar-Av (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Ba (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Beck, G. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Beg-Berk (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Berl-Berz (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Bes-Bey (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Bh-Bi (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Bl-Bohm (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Bohr (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Bol-Br (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Bu (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Ca (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Ch (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Ci-Co (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Cockcroft, Sir J. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Cohen, S. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Co-Cy (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Da-De (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Dh-Di (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Do-Dy (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Dostrovsky, I. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Ec-En (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Er-Ex (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Fa (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Fe (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Fi (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Fl-Fo (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Fr (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Fujiwara, S. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Ga (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Gi-Gl (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Goe-Gol (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Goo-Gou (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Gre (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Gri-Gru (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Gu (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Ha (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Hahn, E. (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - He (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Heisenberg, W. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Hi-Hofstadter, L. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Hofstadter, R., (1954-64) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Hofstadter, R., (1965-73) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Ho-Hu (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - I (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Ja (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Jeffries, C. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Jh-Ju (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Ka (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Ke (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Kh-Ki (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Kl-Kr (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Ku (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - La-Le (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Li (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Lockspeiser, Sir B. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Lod-Lor (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Los-Lu (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Mac-Man (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Marois, M. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Mar-Maz (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Mc (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Me (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Meyerhof, W. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Middleton, M., (1964-71) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Middleton, M., (1972-76) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Mi (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Mo-Mu (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - N (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - O (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Pa (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Pe (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Perrin, F. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Pf-Pl (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Po-Q (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Rabi, I. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Rab-Raj (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Rama Rao, I. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Ram-Ray (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Re-Rog (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Rorschach, H. E., (1964-69) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Rorschach, H. E., (1970-76) (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Rorschach, H. E., (1976-81) (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Ros-Ry (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Sa (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Sch (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Schick, M. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Schiff, L., (1946-55) (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Schiff, L., (1956-68) (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Sc-Se (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Sh (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Shockley, W., (1968) (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Shockley, W., (1968) (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Shockley, W., (1966-1972) (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Si-Sl (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Sm-So (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Spaeth, C. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Sp (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Sr (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Sta-Ste (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Sto-Stu (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Su-Sz (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Ta-Th (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Telegdi, V. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Tieche, C. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Ti-Tz (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - U (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Valeur, R. (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - V (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Wa (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Wea-Wee (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Wei-Wet (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Wh-Wi (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Wilson, C. W. (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Wo-Wy (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Y (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Yang, C. N. (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Z (Box 9, Folder 24)
- PHYSICS DEPARTMENT, SERIES II
  Series II contains materials relating to the organization and activities of the Stanford University Physics Department. Included are memos, minutes, lecture notes, notes on and drafts of tributes to colleagues, and plans for physics buildings.
  - DEPARTMENT MINUTES
    Minutes and memos from departmental proceedings are organized chronologically and provide a fairly complete record of departmental activities from 1954 through 1982.
    - 1954-55 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - January-March 1956 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - April 1956 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - May-July 1956 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - August-December 1956 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - January-June 1957 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - July-December 1957 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - January-April 1958 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - May-September 1958 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - October-December 1958 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - January-June 1959 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - August-December 1959 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - January-September 1960 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - October-November 18 1960 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - November 21-December 1960 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - January-May 1961 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - June-September 1961 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - October-December 1961 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - January-May 1962 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - June-September 1962 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - October-November 1962 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - December 1962 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - January-February 1963 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - March-June 1963 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - July-September 1963 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - October-December 1963 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - 1964 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - January-April 1965 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - May-July 1965 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - August-December 1965 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - January-September 1966 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - October-December 1966 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - 1967 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - April-September 1968 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - October 1968 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - November-December 1968 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - January 1969 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - February-August 1969 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - September-December 1969 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - January-July 1970 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - August-October 1970 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - November-December 1970 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - January-March 1971 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - April 1971 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - May-September 1971 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - October-December 1971 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - January-March 1972 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - April-May 1972 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - June-September 1972 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - October-December 1972 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - February-April 1973 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - May-December 1973 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - February-July 1974 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - August-October 1974 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - November-December 1974 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - January-May 1975 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - June-December 1975 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - January-June 1976 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - July-December 1976 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - 1977 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - 1978 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - 1979 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - 1980 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - January-March 1981 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - April-December 1981 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - January-April 1982 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - May-September 1982 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - October 1982 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - November 1982 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - December 1982 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - 1983 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - DEPARTMENT AND UNIVERSITY COMMITTEES
    This section, arranged alphabetically by committee, contains records from several committees on which Bloch served during his years at Stanford. Included are minutes, memos, and reports of the Graduate Study Committee, the Chemistry Advisory Panel, the Applied Physics Division Committee, and the Academic Council. Most of these records are incomplete and may be compared to records of these committees located elsewhere in the Stanford University Archives.
    - Academic Council (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Applied Physics Division Committee. Minutes and memos, (1962). (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Chemistry Advisory Committee. Correspondence, (1957). (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Committee on International Studies, (1962). (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Committee on International Studies, (1963). (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Committee on International Studies, (1963). (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Committee on International Studies. SRI Draft Report on Overseas Development, (1962). (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Committee on International Studies. Ford Foundation Proposal. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Committee on International Studies. SRI Report, (1963). (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Graduate Study Committee, (1963). (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Graduate Study Committee, (1-4/1964). (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Graduate Study Committee, (5-7/1964). (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Graduate Study Committee, (10/1964-4/1965). (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Graduate Study Committee, (5-12/1965). (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Graduate Study Committee, (1-2/1966). (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Graduate Study Committee, (3-11/1966). (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Graduate Study Committee, (1-9/1967). (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - LECTURE NOTES
    Bloch kept very thorough lecture notes. The notes collected here cover his entire teaching career at Stanford (1933-1971) and are arranged chronologically within each course. His notes for Physics 171, Thermodynamics, are particularly extensive. Also of interest is the typed manuscript for his 1969 class on Many-Body Theory.
    - Thermodynamics Part 1., (undated). (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Thermodynamics Part 2., (undated). (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Thermodynamics, (undated). (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Thermodynamics Part 1., (undated). (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Thermodynamics Part 2., (undated). (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Thermodynamics Part 3., (undated). (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Thermodynamics Part 1., (1963). (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Thermodynamics Part 2., (1963). (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Thermodynamics, (1964). (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Thermodynamics Part 1., (1966). (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Thermodynamics Part 2., (1966). (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Thermodynamics, (1972-73). (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Thermodynamics. Problem sets, (1934-72). (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Thermodynamics. Drafts of problem sets. (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Thermodynamics. Solution sets. (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Thermodynamics. Solution sets. (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Thermodynamics. Solution sets. (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Thermodynamics. Solution sets. (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Thermodynamics. Grading and administration. (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Kinetic Theory, (1934-35). (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Kinetic Theory Part 1., (1959-60). (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Kinetic Theory Part 2., (1959-60). (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Kinetic Theory, (1968-69). (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Kinetic Theory Part 1., (1969). (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Kinetic Theory Part 2., (1969). (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Kinetic Theory Part 1., (1969-70). (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Kinetic Theory Part 2., (1969-70). (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Kinetic Theory. Problem sets, grading, drafts, (1934-71). (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Kinetic Theory. Solution sets. (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Relativity Part 1., (undated). (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Relativity Part 2., (undated). (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Quantum Mechanics Part 1., (undated). (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Quantum Mechanics Part 2., (undated). (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Quantum Mechanics, (undated). (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Quantum Electrodynamics Part 1., (1949). (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Quantum Electrodynamics Part 2., (1949). (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Quantum Electrodynamics Part 3., (1949). (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Quantum Electrodynamics Part 4., (1949). (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Optics, (undated). (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Optics, (1963). (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Optics, (1963). (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Optics, (1964). (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Optics Part 1., (1964). (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Optics Part 2., (1964). (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Optics Part 3., (1964). (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Optics, (1966). (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Optics, (1967). (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Optics. Problem sets and drafts. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Optics. Exams and drafts. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Optics. Exams and drafts. (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Elementary Electricity and Magnetism, (1950). (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Elementary Electricity and Magnetism, (1952-53). (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Elementary Electricity and Magnetism Part 2., (1952-53). (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Elementary Electricity and Magnetism Part 3., (1952-53). (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Electric & Magnetic Fields, (undated). (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Analytical Mechanics, (undated). (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Nuclear Theory Part 1., (1952-53). (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Nuclear Theory Part 2., (1952-53). (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Nuclear Theory Part 1., (undated). (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Nuclear Theory Part 2., (undated). (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Nuclear Moments Part 1., (undated). (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Nuclear Moments Part 2., (undated). (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Nuclear Moments Part 1., (1960). (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Nuclear Moments Part 2., (1960). (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Nuclear Moments Part 1., (undated). (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Nuclear Moments Part 2., (undated). (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Nuclear Moments. Problem sets and drafts, (1960). (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Nuclear Dispersion, (undated). (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - The Neutron-Proton System, (undated). (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Mathematical Physics. Problem sets, (1933-57). (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Theory of Collisions, (undated). (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Nuclear Many-Body Theory manuscript, (1968-69). (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Nuclear Many-Body Theory manuscript Part 2., (1968-69). (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Nuclear Many-Body Theory manuscript Part 3., (1968-69). (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Nuclear Many-Body Theory manuscript Part 4., (1968-69). (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Nuclear Many-Body Theory manuscript Part 5., (1968-69). (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Nuclear Many-Body Theory manuscript Part 6., (1968-69). (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Nuclear Many-Body Theory manuscript Part 7., (1968-69). (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Nuclear Many-Body Theory manuscript Part 8., (1968-69). (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Nuclear Many-Body Theory manuscript Part 9., (1968-69). (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Nuclear Many-Body Theory manuscript Part 10., (1968-69). (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Nuclear Many-Body Theory manuscript Part 11., (1968-69). (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Nuclear Many-Body Theory manuscript Part 12., (1968-69). (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Quantum Mechanics Part 1., (undated). (Box 20 (oversize), Folder 1)
    - Quantum Mechanics Part 2., (undated). (Box 20 (oversize), Folder 2)
    - Electromagnetism Part 1., (undated). (Box 20 (oversize), Folder 3)
    - Electromagnetism Part 2., (undated). (Box 20 (oversize), Folder 4)
    - Allegmeine Relativitatstheorie Part 1., (1930?). (Box 20 (oversize), Folder 5)
    - Allegmeine Relativitatstheorie Part 2., (1930?) (Box 20 (oversize), Folder 6)
  - PLANS AND BUILDINGS
    In the late 1950's, the Physics Department began working out plans for a new physics building. During this period, Bloch collected information on other universities' physics buildings and corresponded with architects, colleagues, and administrators regarding fund-raising. The correspondence within this section is arranged chronologically and is followed by plans of various buildings.
    - Correspondence, (11/55-5/56). (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, (6-9/1956). (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, (10/56-1/57). (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, (1-4/1957). (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, (5-6/1957). (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, (7-10/1957). (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, (11/57-1/58). (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, (2/58-3/59). (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - 'Study for Proposed Physics Group' and revised plans for lighting lecture hall, (1950). (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - 'Proposal for a Physics Teaching and Research Building', (undated, c. 1956). (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Plans for physics buildings. U. of Pennsylvania. (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Plans for physics buildings. U. Penn., (1949). (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Plans for physics buildings. U. Penn., (1949). (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Plans for physics buildings. U. Penn., (1949). (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Plans for physics buildings. U. Penn., (1949). (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Plans for physics buildings. Misc. universities. (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Notes on building plans, (1958). (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - TRIBUTES TO COLLEAGUES